[
  {
    "id": 4601,
    "question": "isla",
    "questionDetails": "La isla de Man.",
    "answer": "isle",
    "answerDetails": "The Isle of Man."
  },
  {
    "id": 4602,
    "question": "jodiendo",
    "questionDetails": "Eso apesta a ti jodiendo con la gente.",
    "answer": "screwing, kidding, kidding me",
    "answerDetails": "It just reeks of you screwing with people."
  },
  {
    "id": 4603,
    "question": "tranquilas",
    "questionDetails": "Se quedaron tranquilas, sus mandíbulas de trabajo.",
    "answer": "quiet, calm, tranquil",
    "answerDetails": "They stood quiet, their jaws working."
  },
  {
    "id": 4604,
    "question": "cagada",
    "questionDetails": "Traes el parabrisas lleno de cagadas de paloma.",
    "answer": "crap",
    "answerDetails": "Your windshield is covered in pigeon crap."
  },
  {
    "id": 4605,
    "question": "párate",
    "questionDetails": "Párate junto a la puerta.",
    "answer": "stand",
    "answerDetails": "Stand against the door."
  },
  {
    "id": 4606,
    "question": "escondiendo",
    "questionDetails": "Debes estas escondiendo algo.",
    "answer": "hiding, hidin’, stashing",
    "answerDetails": "You must be hiding something."
  },
  {
    "id": 4607,
    "question": "debiste",
    "questionDetails": "Le debiste de dar su lugar.",
    "answer": "should",
    "answerDetails": "You should give it to her instead."
  },
  {
    "id": 4608,
    "question": "incendio",
    "questionDetails": "El incendio se descontroló y se quemaron 2 fábricas cercanas.",
    "answer": "fire, blaze",
    "answerDetails": "The fire got out of control and burned two nearby factories."
  },
  {
    "id": 4609,
    "question": "servirle",
    "questionDetails": "Si desea servirle, baje la bandera …",
    "answer": "serve",
    "answerDetails": "If you wish to serve it, take down that flag …"
  },
  {
    "id": 4610,
    "question": "traicionar",
    "questionDetails": "No debo traicionar esa confianza.",
    "answer": "betray",
    "answerDetails": "I must not betray that trust."
  },
  {
    "id": 4611,
    "question": "acompáñeme",
    "answer": "Join me"
  },
  {
    "id": 4612,
    "question": "agradecida",
    "questionDetails": "Te estaré eternamente agradecida.",
    "answer": "grateful, thankful, appreciative",
    "answerDetails": "I will be eternally grateful to you."
  },
  {
    "id": 4613,
    "question": "suéltalo",
    "answer": "Release it"
  },
  {
    "id": 4614,
    "question": "limón",
    "questionDetails": "Y té con limón.",
    "answer": "lemon",
    "answerDetails": "And tea with lemon."
  },
  {
    "id": 4615,
    "question": "confundida",
    "questionDetails": "Pero quizás solo estaba confundida en este nuevo ambiente.",
    "answer": "confused, confounded, mistaken",
    "answerDetails": "But maybe she’s just confused in this new environment."
  },
  {
    "id": 4616,
    "question": "andamos",
    "questionDetails": "Cuando nosotros andamos en caminos de pecado.",
    "answer": "walk",
    "answerDetails": "When we walk on roads of sin."
  },
  {
    "id": 4617,
    "question": "raya",
    "questionDetails": "Las cebras tienen rayas blancas y negras.",
    "answer": "stripe, streak, ray",
    "answerDetails": "Zebras have black and white stripes."
  },
  {
    "id": 4618,
    "question": "sospechar",
    "questionDetails": "Si el doble se cae, todos empezarán a sospechar.",
    "answer": "suspect",
    "answerDetails": "If the double faIls off, everyone will suspect."
  },
  {
    "id": 4619,
    "question": "casarte",
    "questionDetails": "Puedes casarte con quien quieras.",
    "answer": "marry, get married",
    "answerDetails": "You can marry anybody you like."
  },
  {
    "id": 4620,
    "question": "asustada",
    "questionDetails": "Yo estaba más asustada de eso.",
    "answer": "scared, frightened, afraid",
    "answerDetails": "I was more scared of that."
  },
  {
    "id": 4621,
    "question": "reto",
    "questionDetails": "El espadachín aceptó el reto de su rival.",
    "answer": "challenge, dare",
    "answerDetails": "The swordsman took up his rival’s challenge."
  },
  {
    "id": 4622,
    "question": "deseos",
    "questionDetails": "Brisas amistosas, ayuden los deseos de los buenos corazones.",
    "answer": "desires, wishes, lusts",
    "answerDetails": "Friendly breezes, favor the desires of such good hearts."
  },
  {
    "id": 4623,
    "question": "cristo",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 4624,
    "question": "oreja",
    "questionDetails": "¡ Caramba! ¡ Mira qué orejas más grandes tiene!.",
    "answer": "lug",
    "answerDetails": "Blimey, look at the size of those lugs!."
  },
  {
    "id": 4625,
    "question": "injusticia",
    "questionDetails": "Lo que te hicieron fue una injusticia papá.",
    "answer": "injustice",
    "answerDetails": "What they did to you was an injustice, dad."
  },
  {
    "id": 4626,
    "question": "actividades",
    "questionDetails": "Tienen actividades excelentes para los aspirantes.",
    "answer": "activities, efforts",
    "answerDetails": "They have great activities for prospective freshmen."
  },
  {
    "id": 4627,
    "question": "estuviéramos",
    "questionDetails": "Como si estuviéramos malditos.",
    "answer": "were",
    "answerDetails": "As if it were cursed."
  },
  {
    "id": 4628,
    "question": "desgraciadamente",
    "questionDetails": "Desgraciadamente, murieron en el accidente.",
    "answer": "unfortunately, sadly",
    "answerDetails": "Unfortunately, they died in the accident."
  },
  {
    "id": 4629,
    "question": "exagerado",
    "questionDetails": "El informe exagerado de ganancias llevó a un aumento injustificado en el precio de las acciones de la compañía.",
    "answer": "inflated",
    "answerDetails": "The inflated earnings report led to an unjustified increase in the company’s stock price."
  },
  {
    "id": 4630,
    "question": "prepare",
    "questionDetails": "Se prepare para moverse.",
    "answer": "prepare, prep",
    "answerDetails": "Prepare to be moved."
  },
  {
    "id": 4631,
    "question": "conste",
    "questionDetails": "conste que encontrar el defensor público …",
    "answer": "record",
    "answerDetails": "record i find the public defender …"
  },
  {
    "id": 4632,
    "question": "equivocando",
    "questionDetails": "Estás equivocando tu amabilidad con debilidad.",
    "answer": "wrong",
    "answerDetails": "You wrong your kindness for weakness."
  },
  {
    "id": 4633,
    "question": "preferido",
    "questionDetails": "La fuerza no es nuestro modo preferido de manejar estas situaciones.",
    "answer": "preferred, favored",
    "answerDetails": "Force is not our preferred way to handle these situations."
  },
  {
    "id": 4634,
    "question": "autobús",
    "questionDetails": "Tomamos el autobús de las 7 am a Santiago de Chile.",
    "answer": "coach, bus",
    "answerDetails": "We took the 7 A.M. coach to Santiago in Chile."
  },
  {
    "id": 4635,
    "question": "celebración",
    "questionDetails": "La celebración de fin de año promete ser espectacular.",
    "answer": "celebration, festivity",
    "answerDetails": "The year-end celebration promises to be spectacular."
  },
  {
    "id": 4636,
    "question": "valga",
    "questionDetails": "Espero que valga la pena.",
    "answer": "worth",
    "answerDetails": "Hope it was worth it."
  },
  {
    "id": 4637,
    "question": "ciudadano",
    "questionDetails": "Todo ciudadano tiene sus derechos.",
    "answer": "citizen",
    "answerDetails": "Every citizen has rights."
  },
  {
    "id": 4638,
    "question": "asesinado",
    "questionDetails": "Yo era el socio del hombre asesinado.",
    "answer": "murdered, killed, assassinated",
    "answerDetails": "I was the murdered man’s partner."
  },
  {
    "id": 4639,
    "question": "ayudara",
    "questionDetails": "Sería una bendición si nos ayudara.",
    "answer": "help",
    "answerDetails": "It will be a blessing if you help us."
  },
  {
    "id": 4640,
    "question": "cultura",
    "questionDetails": "La cultura griega es rica en historia y tradición.",
    "answer": "culture, education, arts",
    "answerDetails": "Greek culture is rich with history and tradition."
  },
  {
    "id": 4641,
    "question": "muevo",
    "questionDetails": "Me muevo más rápido solo.",
    "answer": "move",
    "answerDetails": "I move faster alone."
  },
  {
    "id": 4642,
    "question": "cuidarme",
    "questionDetails": "… están aquí, querían cuidarme.",
    "answer": "take care",
    "answerDetails": "… are here, they wanted to take care."
  },
  {
    "id": 4643,
    "question": "promesas",
    "questionDetails": "Las promesas en el futuro serán aún más impredecibles.",
    "answer": "promises, pledges, vows",
    "answerDetails": "The future promises to be even more unpredictable."
  },
  {
    "id": 4644,
    "question": "salidas",
    "questionDetails": "Cables y salidas del amplificador.",
    "answer": "outputs, exits, departures",
    "answerDetails": "Cables and amplifier outputs."
  },
  {
    "id": 4645,
    "question": "conversaciones",
    "questionDetails": "El propósito de las conversaciones es llegar a un acuerdo sobre el tema nuclear.",
    "answer": "talks",
    "answerDetails": "The purpose of the talks was to come to an agreement over the nuclear issue."
  },
  {
    "id": 4646,
    "question": "recuperación",
    "questionDetails": "Las condiciones climáticas dificultaron la recuperación de los cuerpos de los dos montañeros.",
    "answer": "retrieval, recovery, recuperation",
    "answerDetails": "Weather conditions have hindered the retrieval of the two mountaineers’ bodies."
  },
  {
    "id": 4647,
    "question": "masa",
    "questionDetails": "Una masa de nubarrones anunciaba la llegada de una tormenta.",
    "answer": "mass, body, batter",
    "answerDetails": "A mass of grey clouds announced the coming of a storm."
  },
  {
    "id": 4648,
    "question": "indicado",
    "questionDetails": "Este gel es muy suave, e indicado para todos los tipos de piel.",
    "answer": "suitable",
    "answerDetails": "This gel is very gentle and suitable for all skin types."
  },
  {
    "id": 4649,
    "question": "querrá",
    "questionDetails": "Sé que querrá una taza de café cuando despierte, así que déjeme mostrarle dónde está la cafetera.",
    "answer": "you will want",
    "answerDetails": "I know you will want a cup of coffee when you wake up, so let me show you where the coffee maker is."
  },
  {
    "id": 4650,
    "question": "receta",
    "questionDetails": "No hay una receta para la felicidad.",
    "answer": "recipe",
    "answerDetails": "There is no recipe for happiness."
  },
  {
    "id": 4651,
    "question": "protegido",
    "questionDetails": "Las plantas necesitan un lugar sombreado y protegido en el jardín.",
    "answer": "sheltered",
    "answerDetails": "The plants need a shady, sheltered spot in the garden."
  },
  {
    "id": 4652,
    "question": "sígueme",
    "questionDetails": "Si no sabes el camino, sígueme en el coche.",
    "answer": "follow me",
    "answerDetails": "If you don’t know the way, follow me in the car."
  },
  {
    "id": 4653,
    "question": "reconocimiento",
    "questionDetails": "Los sistemas de identificación pueden incluir el reconocimiento de imágenes y rostros.",
    "answer": "recognition, appreciation, acknowledgment",
    "answerDetails": "Identification systems can include the recognition of images and faces."
  },
  {
    "id": 4654,
    "question": "raíz",
    "questionDetails": "Para poder curarla, necesitamos averiguar cuál es la raíz de la enfermedad.",
    "answer": "root cause",
    "answerDetails": "To be able to cure it, we need to figure out what the root cause of the illness is."
  },
  {
    "id": 4655,
    "question": "pensaría",
    "questionDetails": "Pero la gente pensaría que lo hiciste.",
    "answer": "think",
    "answerDetails": "But people will think you did."
  },
  {
    "id": 4656,
    "question": "principales",
    "questionDetails": "Los motores principales comienzan en cuatro minutos.",
    "answer": "main, major, principal",
    "answerDetails": "Main engines start in four minutes."
  },
  {
    "id": 4657,
    "question": "falleció",
    "answer": "Died"
  },
  {
    "id": 4658,
    "question": "hilo",
    "questionDetails": "Ella puso su aguja y el hilo de distancia.",
    "answer": "thread, wire, strand",
    "answerDetails": "She put her needle and thread away."
  },
  {
    "id": 4659,
    "question": "mínima",
    "questionDetails": "Apunto de cruzar altura mínima de crucero.",
    "answer": "minimum, min, lowest",
    "answerDetails": "About to cross minimum cruise height."
  },
  {
    "id": 4660,
    "question": "bajes",
    "questionDetails": "Será mejor que la bajes, amigo.",
    "answer": "down",
    "answerDetails": "Better put it down then, mate."
  },
  {
    "id": 4661,
    "question": "harán",
    "questionDetails": "Te harán pagar extra para la entrega.",
    "answer": "they will make",
    "answerDetails": "They will make you pay extra for delivery."
  },
  {
    "id": 4662,
    "question": "arreglarlo",
    "questionDetails": "Llama a alguien que venga a arreglarlo.",
    "answer": "fix it",
    "answerDetails": "Call someone to come over and fix it."
  },
  {
    "id": 4663,
    "question": "efectos",
    "questionDetails": "Después de sobrevivir el huracán, todos sus efectos personales cabían en una sola caja.",
    "answer": "effects",
    "answerDetails": "After surviving the hurricane, all his personal effects could fit into one Box."
  },
  {
    "id": 4664,
    "question": "naciste",
    "questionDetails": "Tú que naciste ciego deberías entender la empatía …",
    "answer": "born",
    "answerDetails": "You of all people, born blind should understand empathy …"
  },
  {
    "id": 4665,
    "question": "roba",
    "questionDetails": "Ya sabes, la que roba niños.",
    "answer": "steals, robs",
    "answerDetails": "You know, who steals children."
  },
  {
    "id": 4666,
    "question": "impacto",
    "questionDetails": "En el momento del impacto.",
    "answer": "impact",
    "answerDetails": "On impact."
  },
  {
    "id": 4667,
    "question": "causas",
    "questionDetails": "El héroe de causas perdidas.",
    "answer": "causes, reasons, cases",
    "answerDetails": "The hero of lost causes."
  },
  {
    "id": 4668,
    "question": "ventanas",
    "answer": "Windows"
  },
  {
    "id": 4669,
    "question": "volveremos",
    "questionDetails": "Volveremos con comida para los hambrientos.",
    "answer": "we will return",
    "answerDetails": "We will return with food for the hungry."
  },
  {
    "id": 4670,
    "question": "pisar",
    "questionDetails": "Deberías pisar con cuidado.",
    "answer": "tread",
    "answerDetails": "You should tread carefully."
  },
  {
    "id": 4671,
    "question": "regalado",
    "questionDetails": "Pensé que la habías regalado.",
    "answer": "given, gifted",
    "answerDetails": "I thought you’d given it."
  },
  {
    "id": 4672,
    "question": "neta",
    "questionDetails": "No hay suficiente fuerza neta para alcanzar el levantamiento aerodinámico.",
    "answer": "net",
    "answerDetails": "Not enough net force to achieve aerodynamic lift."
  },
  {
    "id": 4673,
    "question": "pará",
    "answer": "Pará"
  },
  {
    "id": 4674,
    "question": "franco",
    "questionDetails": "El candidato principal es un Franco detractor del sistema público de salud.",
    "answer": "outspoken",
    "answerDetails": "The primary candidate is an outspoken critic of the healthcare system."
  },
  {
    "id": 4675,
    "question": "entendés",
    "questionDetails": "Y además yo siempre le digo,¿entendés?",
    "answer": "understand",
    "answerDetails": "I always tell her, do you understand?"
  },
  {
    "id": 4676,
    "question": "selva",
    "questionDetails": "Política de poder reflejaba la ley de la selva.",
    "answer": "jungle, forest",
    "answerDetails": "Power politics reflected the law of the jungle."
  },
  {
    "id": 4677,
    "question": "sobrina",
    "questionDetails": "Su sobrina no sabía nada de hombres.",
    "answer": "niece",
    "answerDetails": "Your niece knew nothing of such men."
  },
  {
    "id": 4678,
    "question": "candidato",
    "questionDetails": "Ni un solo candidato aceptable.",
    "answer": "candidate",
    "answerDetails": "Not one acceptable candidate."
  },
  {
    "id": 4679,
    "question": "tequila",
    "questionDetails": "Tú hueles a tequila.",
    "answer": "tequila",
    "answerDetails": "You smell like tequila."
  },
  {
    "id": 4680,
    "question": "galán",
    "questionDetails": "Marlon es sólo un empleado de oficina, pero se esfuerza por vestirse siempre como un galán.",
    "answer": "beau",
    "answerDetails": "Marlon is just a clerk in an office, but he strives to always dress like a beau."
  },
  {
    "id": 4681,
    "question": "amiguita",
    "questionDetails": "Esto es todo lo que queda de tu amiguita.",
    "answer": "girlfriend, playmate",
    "answerDetails": "This is all that’s left of your girlfriend."
  },
  {
    "id": 4682,
    "question": "soldados",
    "questionDetails": "Tuvimos que destinar más de 2, 000 soldados al extranjero para ayudar con el esfuerzo bélico.",
    "answer": "troops",
    "answerDetails": "We had to deploy over 2,000 troops abroad to aid in the war effort."
  },
  {
    "id": 4683,
    "question": "espéreme",
    "questionDetails": "Usted solo espéreme aquí en la mesa.",
    "answer": "wait",
    "answerDetails": "You just wait here at the table."
  },
  {
    "id": 4684,
    "question": "gimnasio",
    "questionDetails": "Repito, apoyo al gimnasio.",
    "answer": "gymnasium",
    "answerDetails": "I repeat, backup in the gymnasium!"
  },
  {
    "id": 4685,
    "question": "nieta",
    "questionDetails": "Mi nieta tenía un demonio.",
    "answer": "granddaughter",
    "answerDetails": "My granddaughter had a demon in her."
  },
  {
    "id": 4686,
    "question": "suéltala",
    "questionDetails": "Suéltala y muéstreme sus manos.",
    "answer": "drop",
    "answerDetails": "Drop it and show me your hands."
  },
  {
    "id": 4687,
    "question": "cancha",
    "questionDetails": "Mi complejo residencial tiene una cancha de tenis.",
    "answer": "court",
    "answerDetails": "My apartment complex has a tennis court."
  },
  {
    "id": 4688,
    "question": "pizza",
    "questionDetails": "Gracias por la pizza.",
    "answer": "pizza",
    "answerDetails": "Thanks for the pizza."
  },
  {
    "id": 4689,
    "question": "préstamo",
    "questionDetails": "Pagamos el préstamo bancario antes de la fecha estipulada en el contrato.",
    "answer": "loan",
    "answerDetails": "We repaid the bank loan before the date agreed on in the contract."
  },
  {
    "id": 4690,
    "question": "maquillaje",
    "questionDetails": "Taylor se pone maquillaje todas las mañanas antes de salir de la casa.",
    "answer": "makeup",
    "answerDetails": "Taylor puts her makeup on every morning before leaving the house."
  },
  {
    "id": 4691,
    "question": "armados",
    "questionDetails": "Los sospechosos están probablemente armados y son peligrosos.",
    "answer": "armed, armoured",
    "answerDetails": "Suspects are possibly armed and dangerous."
  },
  {
    "id": 4692,
    "question": "mosca",
    "questionDetails": "Y la vida de una mosca es aún más corta.",
    "answer": "fly",
    "answerDetails": "And the life of a fly is even shorter."
  },
  {
    "id": 4693,
    "question": "fan",
    "answer": "fan"
  },
  {
    "id": 4694,
    "question": "materiales",
    "questionDetails": "Yo deseo pedir los materiales para hacer un testamento.",
    "answer": "materials",
    "answerDetails": "I wish to request materials to make a will."
  },
  {
    "id": 4695,
    "question": "trabaje",
    "answer": "Work"
  },
  {
    "id": 4696,
    "question": "posiblemente",
    "questionDetails": "¿Vas a venir a mi fiesta de cumpleaños?-Posiblemente.",
    "answer": "maybe",
    "answerDetails": "Are you coming to my birthday party?-Maybe."
  },
  {
    "id": 4697,
    "question": "novela",
    "questionDetails": "En su última novela, la autora exploró el feminismo y la sexualidad.",
    "answer": "novel",
    "answerDetails": "In her last novel, the author explored feminism and sexuality."
  },
  {
    "id": 4698,
    "question": "trates",
    "questionDetails": "No trates de librarte de mí.",
    "answer": "try, treat, tryto",
    "answerDetails": "Do not try to weasel out on me."
  },
  {
    "id": 4699,
    "question": "prepárate",
    "questionDetails": "Prepárate, Janet. Nos vamos en 5 minutos.",
    "answer": "get ready",
    "answerDetails": "Get ready, Janet. We’re leaving in five minutes."
  },
  {
    "id": 4700,
    "question": "explosión",
    "questionDetails": "Dio salida a toda su frustración en una explosión de ira.",
    "answer": "explosion, burst",
    "answerDetails": "All her frustration came out in an explosion of anger."
  }
]